

yorkittran.is-not-a.dev | LinkedIn | GitHub Email: yorkittran@gmail.com | Mobile: +84 366 08 2301

Summary

I am interested in building and improving software systems. I'm now looking for opportunities to work in a high growth and challenging environment with a strong emphasis on engineering effort.

- 2 years of experience in developing application.
- Full stack web developer, with a focus on back-end systems and services.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Ruby, JavaScript

Frameworks/Libraries : Ruby on Rails, Hotwire, NodeJS, VueJS, Express, NestJS

Databases : MySQL, MongoDB

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Github

EXPERIENCE

CodeLink HCMC

Full Stack Developer Oct 2022 – Feb 2023

CodeLink is a multinational development consultancy. We approach product development through design thinking methodologies and strategies to rapidly develop digital products and platforms following a disciplined agile process.

Baonoi

NodeJS, Flutter, ReactJS, Python, Firebase, PostgreSQL

Baonoi is an audio news application that convert from many famous online news in Vietnam. Although still in beta phase, it has around 1000 users using everyday. Mostly I focused on back-end engineering, but in this project I also have a chance to support team to do mobile stuffs.

Raksul Vietnam HCMC

Backend Engineer

Aug 2020 - Oct 2022

Location: District 7, HCMC

Raksul is a fabless B2B platform builder. We aims to change the world by reinventing legacy industry structures with the power of the Internet.

Novelty

Ruby on Rails, VueJS, MySQL, GraphQL

Novelty is a service of Raksul launched in 2020. Novelty connects printing factory and merchandise seller to allow user direct purchase of printed items from our EC platform. Since launch, the service has grown consistently over 300% year-over-year. I was a part of a 10 members team to build, launch and maintain the service.

Cutting cost with Lambda - Hackweek Edition

NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, AWS

We built the prototype in 3 days that processing images through Lambda functions instead of Workers running on ECs. I transformed logic from back-end to Lambda functions, and handled to redirect to API Gateway. As calculation, we saved about 2000\$/month for the company if it successfully applied on other products. Therefore, we won the 1st prize of Value Award in Hackweek competition with held once a year by Raksul Headquarter.

Digital Product NodeJS, MySQL, AWS

Digital Product is an application that allowed venue/ads owners to create QR codes and assign it to banner ads. Then it will be delivered to many different location and the owners can track the effectiveness of them. I built the prototype alone in 4 weeks using many AWSs to create a serverless application. After 6 months of testing, it proved successfully and was integrated into a bigger product.

Area Marketing

Ruby on Rails, VueJS, MySQL, GraphQL, Google APIs

We were rebuilding a legacy service in modern Ruby on Rails to support further business expansion. I worked on an internal admins tool that allows our internal Raksul employees better efficiency in supporting both our customers and third-party suppliers. We aim to build a set of world-class internal tools that would allow us to scale our business without requiring a large increase in customer support team size.

PRO

Ruby on Rails, VueJS, Python, MySQL

Raksul PRO is a new business initiative that will allow other wholesale resellers to purchase and use Raksul's services. I worked in a team of 4 people to build, launch and maintain the service. Beside implementing features on back-end, I also have a chance to learn VueJS by helping create components and pages on front-end side. By using Python, we also create a crawler to make a comparison prices between competing company's products and ours.

Act Brain Vietnam Corporation

HCMC

Backend Engineer Intern

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

Act Brain is the consultants, provide solutions and develop leading software systems in Japan. We have a young and enthusiastic staff, with creativity and professional qualifications.

BPO Shinjin

PHP, Zend Framework, MySQL

BPO Shinjin is an internal product for managing employees by tracking time sheet, build monthly quizzes, etc. Most of the time I spent for support teamates to finish features.

EDUCATION

FPT University

HCMC

Bachelor of Software Engineering with Scholarship

Sep 2017 - Jan 2021

Le Quy Don Gifted High School

Information & Technology Specialized Class

Da Nang Sep 2014 – May 2017

PROJECTS

Quizk

Ruby on Rails, VueJS, Hotwire, MySQL, DigitalOcean

Quizk is a quiz system for University of Medical and Pharmacy in HCMC to operates a internal competition.

- I was responsible for the development and operation of the application. After 2 months of developing, we success to run it in 3 weeks for serving about 3000 new students in university.
- I built the application using Ruby on Rails to create operation site and APIs, designed whole system included database and architecture. Also tried to deploy application to DigitalOcean.